ALEXANDER HILL

DESKTOP ENGINEER

Alexandria, VA
<u>Email Me</u>
<u>LinkedIn Profile</u>
<u>Download Resume</u>

Professional Summary

Accomplished Desktop Engineer experienced in Microsoft Windows Administration, Task Automation and Workstation Compliance. Extensive knowledge of BigFix, Microsoft Deployment Toolkit, PowerShell, and Batch scripting. All of these have been used to markedly improve efficiency of Windows workstation administration in the environment.

Certifications

ITSM

ITIL V3 Foundation, Exin - 2013

Microsoft Azure

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals, Microsoft -December 2022

Microsoft Azure Administrator (In Progress)

Endpoint Management

Microsoft 365 Certified: Modern Desktop Administrator Associate, Microsoft - September 2022

Technical

Microsoft Windows	Powershell Scripting	Service Now
Microsoft 365	Group Policy	JIRA
Microsoft Azure	HCL BigFix	Workstation Compliance
Active Directory	Windows Administration	Vulnerability Remediation
Intune/Endpoint Configuration	Microsoft Deployment Toolkit	Tenable Security Center
Manager	(MDT)	

Experience

GRSI, National Institutes of Health (NIH) Desktop Engineer

2021-Current

Responsible for administering over 3,500 Windows Endpoints using tools such as HCL BigFix, Powershell scripting, Remote Desktop Protocol and Bomgar Remote Support. In charge of running the MDT server to manage three (3) Windows Workstation Images. Perform other Windows Administration and Compliance with Active Directory, Group Policy and Tenable Security Center.

- Wrote PowerShell scripts to run the migration of data of over 2,000 users from their home shares to OneDrive
- Developed tools to streamline common tasks for workstation administration and analysis including Active Directory tasks, BIOS Configuration, and Registry settings for Local and Remote Usage
- Created tasks to automate driver management in MDT, significantly reducing time and effort required to maintain latest drivers on the Deployment Share
- Developed scripts to customize MDT to improve the efficiency of the imaging process
- Wrote script to remediate the Log4j vulnerabilities in the environment causing a 93% drop in Log4j vulnerabilities over the summer of 2022
- Quickly set up BigFix Fixlets and Analyses to deploy and monitor multiple Security Agents to workstations by a shortened deadline
- Wrote custom BigFix Relevance and Fixlets to COTS applications and resolve workstation compliance

- Utilized the JIRA platform to track Tasks and Projects

GDIT, National Institutes of Health (NIH)

2019-2021

Systems Engineer

Focused on using BigFix to improve the security compliance of Endpoints. Also worked supporting the desktop technicians with escaltions and streamlining common tasks

- Responsible for using BigFix to test and install Windows patches to workstations in accordance with maintenance cycle
- $\hbox{-} Created custom scripts and Bigfix jobs as needed to install Third-Party applications with customized install settings$
- Developed scripts that desktop technicians could use to check and set BIOS settings on workstations such as the Asset Tag
- Testing various hardware configurations to ensure compatibility in our environment and our images
- Manage the Windows Workstation Images using MDT
- Wrote or modified documentation involving the Patching and Maintenance procedures for the environment.

GDIT, National Institues of Health (NIH) Sytems Technician III/Team Lead

2018-2019

Served as OIT Desktop Team Lead for the Main Campus Location as well as being the primary support for Executive Officer and staff

- Trusted to provide exceptional support for Office of the Director (OD) staff at the Main Campus location
- Functioned as an escalation point for desktop technicians
- Trained new technicians as they were onboarded to the team
- Assisted Desktop Engineer with workstation patching using BigFix
- Greatly improved workstation replacement efficiency with scripts to back and restore User Data $\,$
- Able to successfully develop process to verify over 2,000 workstations for a vendor recall project
- Authored Standards of Procedure, Work Instructions and other documentation to assist technicians as well as customers

XA Systems, National Institues of Health (NIH) Mid/Senior Desktop Technician

2012-2018

Started as a Mid-Level Desktop Technician and promoted to Senior-Level supporting Windows Endpoints

- Resolved variety of Windows support issues including software such as Office, hardware troubleshooting and network connectivity issues
- Trusted to handle VIP service requests in a timely and efficient manner
- Used Bomgar Support Tool for assisting customers remotely
- Worked with network operations team to maintain the Windows workstation images using MDT
- Developed into Senior level technician and reliable resource for coworkers and VIP support

Education

Old Dominion University - Norfolk, Virginia Electrical Engineering Technology w/ CS Minor — 2007